PERSONAL SUMMARY

Visionary Creative Operations Manager and curious storyteller with over 25 years of technical video knowledge, 15 years of project management & process development, 12 years leading creative production teams, and a knack for finding patterns and solutions. I believe in cultivating a culture of trust through awareness, open communication, and empowerment. My philosophy is positive accountability and honest expectations lead to strong team relationships and innovative collaboration.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

NicholiNoah.com LLC Oklahoma City, OK 2018-present **AR/VR Creative Education and Content Production**

- Created Open Source VR Education tools with devs from Microsoft and Google
- AR/VR Team Collaboration, Logistics, and Creative Content Production
- Vast knowledge of VR and extended reality systems, processes, and culture

University of Central Oklahoma Edmond, OK 2017-2018 Video Studio Operations Manager (eLearning)

- Lead, assigned & scheduled three member eLearning studio production team
- Integrated project planning and collaboration software template and training
- Produced weekly status reports including forecast of upcoming productions
- Developed 360° augmented reality Construction Management program

Daniel Brian Advertising Detroit, MI 2012-2017 Video Studio Operations Manager // Editor

- Streamlined interdepartmental communication with kick-off task assignments
- Hired, trained, and mentored junior video editor and contributing creatives
- Ensured quality control, final delivery, & systematic archival of all audio/video
- Actively contributed to Creative Team projects (brainstorms, pitches, solutions)
- Responsible for annual, multi-regional Emmy and Telly awards submissions
- Conserved \$30k by restructuring outdated broadcast media delivery system

University of Central Oklahoma Edmond, OK 2015-2011 **Operations Manager, University Video Services**

- Founded and operated video services department with three-member team
- Technical Directed and equipment managed 100+live multicamera productions
- Client-focused business model raised \$25k toward UCO rebranding innitiative
- Mentored student creatives for three semesters of Video Magazine Production

EDUCATION & TRAINING

Manager Development Program

University of Central Oklahoma | Edmond, OK 2019

BA Communication & Professional Media

University of Central Oklahoma | Edmond, OK 2002

Advanced Storytelling Workshop

National Press Photographers Association | Austin, TX 2012

News Video Workshop

National Press Photographers Association | Norman, OK 2010

CHARACTERISTICS

- Team-Serving Leader
- Diverse Communicator
- Accomplishment Driven
- Collaborative Coach
- Proactive Thinker
- Quality Assurance

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS & TOOLSETS

• Team Collaboration

• Project Planning

(Microsoft Teams, Jira, Trello, GitHub) (MS Project, Smartsheet, Gantt Chart)

• Multimedia Production

(Audio/Video, Design, Animation)

Adobe Creative Cloud

(Premiere, AE, Illustrator, Photoshop)

HONORS & AWARDS

- NATAS Upper Midwest Regional EMMY® (2014: Campaign)
- NATAS Ohio Valley Regional EMMY® (2013: Commercial)

INTERESTS & HOBBIES







Travel

Mindfulness